lauraashley.com 2018-10-17

# privacy and cookie policy | Laura Ashley

Laura Ashley is committed to maintaining the security of your data and respecting your privacy rights, whether you visit our stores, browse online or contact us. We want you to have confidence in how we use your data, and your internet security with us, so everything you need to know about your data and how it’s collected can be found below. 

  * Try to use different passwords for each of your online accounts. This way if one is ever compromised, the others remain inaccessible to unauthorised parties. Multiple passwords keep your information safer 
  * Keep passwords private and do not share accounts
  * Avoid passwords that contain common phrases like ‘password’, your own name, or details like your phone number
  * Try to use a mixture of upper and lower case letters, numbers, and special characters to make passwords stronger. We recommend making a password 8 characters or longer 
  * Laura Ashley will never ask you to confirm any bank details or credit card details via email, post, or phone. If you receive an email requesting this information that claims to be from us, we recommend that you ignore it. If you’re contacting us regarding an order you have placed please do not include bank or credit card details in your communication
  * To protect your privacy, we can only discuss an account or order with the account holder or individual that placed the order 
  * When you finish shopping online in a public location, logging out of any accounts you have used helps to ensure your data remains secure 

The privacy and security of any payments you make with us are high priorities. We ensure your payment and personal details are protected when you shop with us.

  * The Laura Ashley website uses high-level, industry standard SSL Encryption (Secure Sockets Layer) technology. Currently, this is the most advanced security software available for online transactions 
  * Any sensitive information, such as credit card details, that you share with us is encrypted. This means information passed between your computer and our website cannot be read even in the unlikely event that it is intercepted by an unauthorised party
  * We strongly recommend that you only connect to secure wireless networks that you trust. Using unsecured networks like those in public places can pose a risk 
  * You are always able to check that a page is secure as the beginning of the URL at the top of the page will change from ‘http’ to ‘https’ when you are browsing a protected page. A locked padlock symbol will also appear at the bottom of your window 
  * Our checkout processes involve security checks from third party services to keep your existing card account protected against any unauthorised use when you shop with us. We work with Verified by Visa and Mastercard ® Securecode ™ to keep your information safe 
  * When purchasing via our mailorder channel, we will not request your card number, you will be referred to our encrypted service where the transaction will be completed securely
  * When purchasing in-store, Mastercard provide our Managed Payment Service software. This is a fully integrated solution, which includes software for handing Point of Sale transactions. Software is certified as PCI compliant. Pin Entry Devices, certified to level PTS3 

Your data is yours, and you have the right to ask what personal data we hold about you at any time. If you ever wish to know the data that Laura Ashley has of yours, please see the Your Rights section at the end of this document.

How We Protect Your Data: 

  * Laura Ashley fully complies with all applicable Data Protection and consumer legislation, and we treat any information shared with us as confidential
  * Customer information is held on secure servers
  * We employ security controls which protect the Laura Ashley IT systems from external attack and unauthorised access

Laura Ashley, or third party data processors acting on our behalf, may collect and use the following personal data that you provide us:

  * Personal details such as name, age, date of birth, and gender 
  * Contact details including your phone number, email address, postal address including billing and delivery addresses
  * Payment card details in the event that you place an order with us 
  * Your purchase and order history
  * Your browsing activity on the Laura Ashley websites
  * Preferences, feedback, and survey responses
  * Publically available data including those shared on public platforms, this can also include details shared with us while communicating with our social media teams
  * Personal details given to us during the creation of a Wedding Gift Card 
  * We will not retain your data for any longer than necessary, unless required by a legal obligation 

Why We Collect Your Data, is to provide you with a streamlined, easy-to-use customer experience and is necessary for: 

  * Pursuit of Legitimate Interests.
  * Contractual necessity engaging in commerce regarding products and services 
  * Compliance with Legal Obligations

Contacting you about special offers, promotions, and products or services using the lawful basis of Consent. If you would like to change or withdraw your email marketing consent choices, please update your account details; see 'my account' at[ **www.lauraashley.com**](http://www.lauraashley.com/ "link to Laura Ashley"), and amend your preferences

Below is how we use the data you share with us: 

  * To verify your identity when you shop with us
  * For market research to provide you with more products you love 
  * To allow our customer service representatives to interact with you should you need them 
  * For the prevention and detection of fraud and crime, and related purposes 
  * With your consent, to contact you about special offers, promotions, and products or services that we feel you might be interested in 
  * Selling and supplying goods and services to our customers
  * For instances when we have a legal duty or right to use or disclose your information, for example in legal disputes or when required by a local authority for an investigation 
  * To monitor and improve the Laura Ashley websites
  * In the event that you purchase through the Laura Ashley websites, we will send you an email request which will enable you to review your order
  * For analysis reporting, financial processing , risk management, legal obligations, and monitoring for our day-to-day business 
  * To provide an e-Receipt for store purchases, if you request one 

**Shared Data and Third Parties**

We may also disclose any personal data you allow us to collect to third parties in instances such as those below:

  * During the process application process for our Barclays Interest Free Credit or Laura Ashley Mastercard, we may share your personal information with necessary third parties to enable checks to be carried out. All customers are subject to validation checks and authorisation from the card issuer/credit provider 
  * If you purchase goods from Laura Ashley Group, we may have to disclose your details to our third party service providers to enable your order to be processed and fulfilled 
  * We may share your personal information with necessary third parties to enable checks to be carried out. All our credit and debit card holders are subject to validation checks and authorisation from the card issuer
  * To support our business operations and audit purposes 
  * We may provide reputable organisations information about sales and website usage for the purposes of research and analysis only
  * Your non-personal information may be shared with another member of the Laura Ashley Group of Companies, including our holding company and subsidiaries
  * Your personal information will be shared, safely and securely, with our third party service providers in order to process and fulfil your orders
  * Your email and purchase history may be shared with Trust Pilot to assist with collecting feedback from customers who have had a buying or service experience with Laura Ashley

We like to keep you updated about our best offers and new collections, so with your permission we will send you updates via email, post, or both. This is a completely optional service, and you can opt out at any time. 

  * Our contact with you will be relevant so you can enjoy great deals and new releases 
  * We will only ask you for things like feedback, and never for personal information such as payment details
  * Payment card details in the event that you place an order with us 
  * Tips, guidance, and lifestyle information will help you make the most of our products
  * To leave, you only have to log in to your Laura Ashley account, click on ‘Marketing Preferences’, and uncheck the boxes for anything you don’t wish to receive
  * Alternatively, if you receive an email from us and you no longer want to be subscribed to our mailing list, you can scroll to the bottom and click on ‘unsubscribe’ to stop receiving emails from us. 

Cookies are small data files that are stored on your computer or device when you visit webpages. Like most websites on the internet, Laura Ashley uses cookies to track how you use our website and to make your user experience more enjoyable. Cookies remember things like what you put in your shopping basket, and previous searches. You can turn cookies off, but our website doesn’t work without them and we recommend leaving them on. See below for more information on cookies: 

  * Most web browsers like Google Chrome and Firefox have cookies enabled by default. You can disable them in your settings if you follow the instructions below
  * If you choose to ‘share’ Laura Ashley content over social media such as Facebook, then you may be sent cookies from those websites. We are not responsible for third-party cookies, so please check these websites for their cookie policies
  * Our cookies do not store sensitive information such as your name, address, or payment details 
  * Cookies cannot damage your computer or compromise your account; information from our cookies is encrypted 
  * A Do Not Track feature is offered by some browsers, requesting that your visit isn’t tracked by third party advertising, social media networks, or analytic companies, however our website does not currently respond to DNT requests. There is currently no industry-wide standard agreed upon for the handling of DNT requests, but we will continue to review DNT and other new technologies 

### How to check cookies are enabled on windows platforms

| 

Microsoft Internet Explorer 7, 8 & 9

1\. Select 'Tools' from the top menu of your browser and then select 'Internet options' , then click on the 'Privacy' tab   
2\. Ensure that your Privacy level is set to Medium or below, which will enable cookies in your browser   
3\. Settings above Medium will disable cookies  
  
---|---  
| 

Mozilla Firefox

1\. Select 'Tools' from the top menu of your browser and then select ‘Options' 2. Then select the Privacy icon 3. Click on Cookies, then select 'allow sites to set cookies'  
  
| 

Google Chrome

1\. Select 'Tools' from the top menu of your browser and then select ‘Options' 2. Click the 'Under the Hood' tab, locate the 'Privacy' section, and select the 'Content settings' button 3. Now select 'Allow local data to be set'  
  
| 

Safari

1\. Select the cog icon' from the top menu of your browser and then select ‘Preferences' 2. Select 'Security and, check the option that says 'Block third-party and advertising cookies' 3. Click 'Save'  
  
Sometimes when you visit the Laura Ashley website, you may notice cookies unrelated to Laura Ashley. Web pages containing embedded content, for example YouTube videos, may send you cookies from third-party websites. Please visit these websites for information on their cookies and how to manage them. 

Cookie Name

| 

Cookie Purpose   
  
---|---  
  
Affiliate Cookies

| 

Affiliate Cookies show us how you found our website and which website you came from  
  
Google Tag Manager

| 

Google Tag Manager’s system allows us to control the tags/pixels which are served on to our web pages, and the data passed into those tags or into reporting. For more information please visit [**https://policies.google.com/privacy**](https://policies.google.com/privacy "link to Google")  
  
Google Display Network

| 

These cookies allow us to show you ads based on the products you have viewed on Lauraashley.com. We may recommend alternative styles and colours we believe are relevant to your browsing history. For more information please visit [**https://policies.google.com/privacy**](https://policies.google.com/privacy "link to Laura Ashley")  
  
Google Analytics Tracking 

| 

Google Analytics use cookies to collect data that we analyse to help us improve customer experience on the Laura Ashley website. For more information please visit[ **https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245**](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245 "google")  
  
Venda

| 

These cookies allow lauraashley.com to operate properly, including managing your basket, and whether you're logged in or not  
  
Blueleaf

| 

Our Made to Order and Made to Measure products require us to keep track of your choices as you configure your products, and this is managed by Blueleaf   
  
Silverpop

| 

Our Made to Order and Made to Measure products require us to keep track of your choices as you configure your products, and this is managed by GB Group   
  
SaleCycle

| 

SaleCycle uses cookies to collect information from your device such as products which were recently added to your basket without completion of your order. For more information please visit [**http://www.salecycle.com/service-privacy-notice/.**](http://www.salecycle.com/service-privacy-notice/ "Link to Sale Cycle")  
  
Mention Me

| 

Mention Me processes data needed for the refer-a-friend programme and only sends emails to customers to have actively engaged with the refer-a-friend scheme   
  
Olapic

| 

Used to track a single session throughout the checkout process to monitor interaction with our Olapic widgets. This cookie has a 1 month expiry date. For more information please visit [**http://www.olapic.com/privacy-policy/**](http://www.olapic.com/privacy-policy/ "Link to Olapic")  
  
HotJar

| 

These cookies allow us to measure and observe your behaviour and interactions on our site. This enables us to enhance and improve the customer journey   
  
Facebook Advertising 

| 

The audiences targeted are based on demographics and interests, so they are not custom data files that we uploaded based on our customers information. For more information please visit [**https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update**](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update "Link to Facebook")  
  
PowerReviews

| 

PowerReviews collects information during the purchase process which will results in an invitation to review a customer’s purchase(s). For more information please visit [**https://www.powerreviews.com/powerreviews-com-ad-and-cookie-policy/**](https://www.powerreviews.com/powerreviews-com-ad-and-cookie-policy/ "powerreviews")  
  
Banner advertising across our website and other websites online helps us to show you products you may be interested in, alternate colourways of products you have already viewed, or similar products in other categories. The technology behind these adverts is based on cookies.

For more information on Google Display Network, the company we use to help us create these advertisements **please visit their website for more details.**

We think this kind of advertising makes shopping more enjoyable for you, but if you would like to opt out of relevant content and this kind of advertising permanently, you can by **simply following this link** >. But please be aware that if you delete your cookies then our website won’t be able to tell you have opted out, and you might still find Google banners appearing on other websites.

You can visit **this website** to find out more about cookies on your computer or device set by other companies, and opt out of them if you so choose. This link opens in a new window – unfortunately we cannot guarantee the safety of external websites, so please proceed with caution.

You have rights as an individual which you can exercise in relation to the information we hold about you:

  * the right to ask what personal data that we hold about you
  * the right to ask us to move , delete, update and correct any out-of-date or incorrect personal data, that we hold about you
  * the right to ask us to restrict processing and the right to object to processing regarding the personal data that we hold about about you 
  * the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling about automated decisions 
  * the right to opt out of any marketing communications that we may send you (please update your account details: see 'my account' at www.lauraashley.com, and amend your customer preferences)

If you need to contact us about data privacy it will help us to respond to your enquiry if you complete our online enquiry form, please click on the link to download the form. **Subject Access Request Form 2018**

Alternatively you can email our Data Protection Officer at: dpo@lauraashley.com. Please send the completed form via email dpo@lauraashley.com or post to the following address: 

  * Data Protection Officer
  * HR Department Laura Ashley Ltd
  * Unit E
  * Vastre Enterprise Park
  * Newtown
  * Powys
  * SY16 1DZ

You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office.Further information, including contact details, is available at [**ico.org.uk**.](https://ico.org.uk/ "link to ico")

For more information on Google Display Network, the company we use to help us create these advertisements **please visit their website for more details.**

**Version 1 11/05/2018**

Laura Ashley Ltd is a plc company, Registered in England and Wales under Company No: 531301 with the head office at 27 Bagley Lane, Fulham, London, SW6 2QA
